Guide to the Samson Raphaelson Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Samson Raphaelson Papers,
1916-1982
Raphaelson, Samson, 1896-1983.
19.5 linear ft (ca.7,400 items in 40 boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4078548
Biographical Note
Samson Raphaelson, playwright, screenwriter, and teacher, wrote scenarios for many of the films directed by Ernst Lubitsch from 1931 until 1947, Raphaelson taught screenwriting at Columbia from 1976 until 1982, and also taught at the University of Illinois in 1920/21 and in 1948.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, playscripts, screenplays, scenarios, short stories, and other manuscripts, drafts, photocopies, contracts and other documents, tearsheets, clippings, and other materials relating to his career as a screenwriter, playwright, and author of short stories. Correspondence with friends, students, admirers, and professional colleagues concern his teaching, playwriting, films, articles, photography, and literary topics. There are also two groups of letters from students and readers about his textbook, "The Human Nature of Playwriting" (1949). Among the cataloged correspondence are William Gibson, MacKinlay Kantor, Anna Louise Strong, Louis Untermeyer, and Carl Van Doren. Included are manuscripts, drafts, or photocopies of almost all his films, plays, and short stories, such as playscripts and drafts of his plays, "The Jazz Singer" (1922), "Skylark" (1939), "Jason" (1942), and others; screenplays and scenarios, many in photocopy, of "Trouble in Paradise" (1932), "The Merry Widow" (1934), "The Shop Aroung the Corner" (1940), "Suspicion" (1941), "Heaven Can Wait" (1943), and many other films; and manuscripts, drafts, tearsheets, and printed copies of his short stories and articles of film and television criticism. There are also many clippings and reviews, programs, and other printed materials about his plays and films.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 10 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Arranged Correcpondence
Series III: Manuscripts by Raphaelson
Series IV: Miscellaneous Papers
Series V: Oversize Material
Series VI: Original Inventory
Series VII: Arranged Correspondence
Series VIII: Manuscripts and Documents
Series IX: Miscellaneous Papers
Series X: 1992 Gift
Subjects
Abbott, George, 1887-1995.; Bemelmans, Ludwig, 1898-1962.; Best, Edna, 1900-1974.; Caldwell, Zoe.; Cronyn, Hume.; Cukor, George, 1899-1983.; Dell, Floyd, 1887-1969.; Eaton, Walter Prichard, 1878-1957.; Ervine, St. John G. (St. John Greer), 1883-1971.; Fonda, Henry, 1905-1982.; Gaige, Crosby, 1882-1949.; Gibbons, Floyd Phillips, 1887-1939.; Gibson, William, 1914-2008.; Gordon, Ruth, 1896-1985.; Green, Paul, 1894-1981.; Halsman, Philippe.; Hayes, Helen, 1900-1993.; Hitchcock, Alfred, 1899-1980.; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972.; Howard, Leslie, 1893-1943.; Jessel, George, 1898-1981.; Kantor, MacKinlay, 1904-1977.; Kazan, Elia.; Kelly, Gene, 1912-1996.; Kober, Arthur, 1900-1975.; Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1893-1970.; Lawrence, Gertrude.; Lindsay, Howard, 1889-1968.; Lockridge, Richard, 1898-1982.; Lubitsch, Ernst, 1892-1947.; Luce, Clare Boothe, 1903-1987.; McClintic, Guthrie, 1893-1961.; Macgowan, Kenneth, 1888-1963.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; Parker, Dorothy, 1893-1967.; Rattigan, Terence.; Sheean, Vincent, 1899-1975.; Sherwood, Robert E. (Robert Emmet), 1896-1955.; Simon, Richard Leo, 1899-1960.; Skinner, Otis, 1858-1942.; Strong, Anna Louise, 1885-1970.; Tandy, Jessica.; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977.; Van Doren, Carl, 1885-1950.; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972.; Werfel, Franz, 1890-1945.; Wilson, Sloan, 1920-2003.; Zanuck, Darryl Francis, 1902-1979.; Authors and theater.; Drama--Technique.; Motion picture authorship.; Playwriting.; Scenarios.; Universities and colleges--New York (State)--New York.; Agreements.; Articles.; Autobiographies.; Awards.; Bills (financial).; Birth certificates.; Brochures.; Clippings.; Contracts.; Decrees.; Drafts (literary).; Essays.; Fiction.; Financial records.; Galley proofs.; Interviews.; Inventories.; Lecture notes.; Memoranda.; Notes.; Outlines.; Photographs.; Photoprints.; Playbills.; Press releases.; Programs.; Proofs.; Receipts.; Reminiscences.; Reviews.; Scores.; Scripts.; Sheet music.; Syllabi.; Transcripts.; Authors.; College teachers.; Critics.; Dramaticsts.; Film critics.; Screenwriters; Theatrical producers and directors.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-41. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
10/06/87 M-87-10-06 Raphaelson, Joel Gift
06/25/92 M-92-06-25 Papers Raphaelson, Joel Gift
Gift of Joel Raphaelson, 1987, 1990, & 1992.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Abbott, George (Box 1)
  - Best, Edna (Box 1)
  - Bemelmans, Ludwig (Box 1)
  - Caldwell, Zoe (Box 1)
  - Cronyn, Hume (Box 1)
  - Cronyn, Hume (Box 1)
  - Cukor, George (Box 1)
  - Dell, Floyd (Box 1)
  - Eaton, Walter Prichard (Box 1)
  - Ervine, St John Greer (Box 1)
  - Fonda, Henry (Box 1)
  - Gaige, Crosby (Box 1)
  - Gibbons, Floyd (Box 1)
  - Gibson, William (Box 1)
  - Gordon, Ruth (Box 1)
  - Green, Paul (Box 1)
  - Halsman, Philippe (Box 1)
  - Hayes, Helen (Box 1)
  - Hitchcock, Alfred (Box 1)
  - Hoover, John Edgar (Box 1)
  - Howard, Leslie (Box 1)
  - Jessel, George (Box 1)
  - Kantor, MacKinlay (Box 1)
  - Kazin, Elia (Box 1)
  - Kelly, Gene (Box 1)
  - Kober, Arthur (Box 1)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood (Box 1)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, Gertrude (Box 1)
  - Lawrence, Gertrude (Box 1)
  - Lindsay, Howard (Box 1)
  - Lockridge, Richard (Box 1)
  - Luce, Clare Boothe (Box 1)
  - Macgowan, Kenneth (Box 1)
  - MacLeish, Archibald (Box 1)
  - McClintic, Guthrie (Box 1)
  - Parker, Dorothy (Box 1)
  - Rattigan, Terence (Box 1)
  - Sheean, Vincent (Box 1)
  - Sherwood, Robert Emmet (Box 1)
  - Simon, Richard Leo (Box 1)
  - Skinner, Otis (Box 1)
  - Strong, Anna Louise (Box 1)
  - Tandy, Jessica (Box 1)
  - Untermeyer, Louis (Box 1)
  - Van Doren, Carl (Box 1)
  - Van Doren, Irita (Box 1)
  - Van Doren, Mark (Box 1)
  - Werfel, Franz (Box 1)
  - Wilson, Sloan (Box 1)
  - Zanuck, Darryl Francis (Box 1)
- Series II: Arranged Correcpondence
  - A - M (Box 2)
  - M - Y & Unidentified (Box 3)
- Series III: Manuscripts by Raphaelson
  - Subseries III.1: Fiction
    - Absent Without Leave [Film], 1937, ( Scenario (unproduced, carbon copy) (Box 4)
    - Accent on Youth [Play], Gulf Screen Guild Theatre, 1939, ( Radio script (mimeographed copy) (Box 4)
    - Accent on Youth [Play], NBC Matinee Theatre, [n.d.], ( Television script (mimeographed copy) (Box 4)
    - Accent on Youth [Play], ( Programs, ) (Box 4)
    - Accent on Youth [Play]: Reviews, New York; Vienna; etc., 1935-1959, ( Clippings & mimeographed copies, ) (Box 4)
    - Accent on Youth [Play], 1935, ( Sheet music, printed copy, ) (Box 4)
    - After the Ball [Short Story], ( Typescripts, 3 drafts & a photostat, ) (Box 4)
    - After the Ball [Short Story]: "The First Affair", The Saturday Evening Post, 1958, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 4)
    - Agent Meets Lady [Short Story], 1960-1977, ( Typescripts, unpublished, 5 drafts (partly carbons) (Box 4)
    - Agent Meets Lady, ( Notes & loose pages, ) (Box 4)
    - Angel [Film], 1937, ( Scenario (Xerox copy) (Box 4)
    - Angel [Film], ( Clipping, ) (Box 4)
    - Anniversary [A Shelley Play], 1935-1943, ( Playscript, unfinished, drafts & notes, ) (Box 4)
    - Anything Can Happen In Central Park [Play] See: Mr. Bystander and Miss Passerby [Play] (Box 4)
    - Beautiful MorninG [Story - Hilda Benson], The Saturday Evening Post, 1947, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 5)
    - The Bedroom; a Comedy [Play] See: Here We Are, Alone Together [Play] (Box 5)
    - Before the Fact [Film] See: Suspicion [Film] (Box 5)
    - The Best Years [Film], ( Synopsis (unproduced, typescript) (Box 5)
    - The Bollingers [Short Story], 1949, ( Typescripts (2 carbon copies) (Box 5)
    - The Bollingers [Short Story], ( Typescripts (2 mimeographed copies) (Box 5)
      [Submitted to Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer 1949]
    - Boolie [Play], 1929, ( Playscript (carbon copy, "First revision") (Box 5)
    - Boolie [Play], 1959 & 1964, ( Playscript (act one, drafts) (Box 5)
    - Boolie [Play]: Act One, 1961, ( Playscript, ) (Box 5)
    - Boolie [Play], 1964, (3 copies Playscript, ) (Box 5)
    - [Boolie Play] The Heel, 1959, ( Playscript (2 carbon copies) (Box 5)
      ["Final OK version"]
    - [Boolie Play] The High Sign, 1961, ( Playscript, ) (Box 5)
      ["First draft final version"]
    - [Boolie Play] The Magnificent Heel, 1936, ( Playscript (carbon copy) (Box 5)
      ["Next to last version"]
    - [Boolie Play] The Magnificent Heel, ( Playscript, ) (Box 5)
      ["As produced in Dallas"]
    - [Boolie Play] The Magnificent Heel, 1959, ( Playscript, ) (Box 5)
      ["Act One"]
    - [Boolie Play] The Magnificent Heel, 1959, ( Playscript, ) (Box 5)
      ["1st draft act one"]
    - [Boolie Play], 1961-1967, ( Notes, ) (Box 6)
    - [Boolie Play], 1962-1964, ( Notes, ) (Box 6)
    - [Boolie Play] The Heel, Dallas, 1954, ( Reviews, ) (Box 6)
    - Broken Lullabye [Film] See: The Man I Killed [Film] (Box 6)
    - Bud's "Home-coming" [Short Story], ( Tearsheets from a college magazine, ) (Box 6)
    - Bunny - "Untitled Play", 1958, ( Playscript, ) (Box 6)
    - Bunny - "Untitled Play", 1958, ( Playscript (draft of act one) (Box 6)
    - Bunny - "Untitled Play", 1958, ( Playscript (carbon copies) (Box 6)
    - Bunny - "Untitled Play", 1958, ( Playscript (carbon copy & notes) (Box 6)
    - Bunny - "Untitled Play", 1958, ( Playscript, ) (Box 6)
      ["Rejected"]
    - The Burning Secret [Film], 1951, ( Scenario, ) (Box 6)
      [Unproduced]
    - Carole [Short Story], Everybody's Magazine, 1923, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 6)
    - Casanova [Film], 1935, ( Typescript (carbon copy) film treatment, ) (Box 6)
    - A Christmas Present [Play], 1954, ( Playscript (carbon copy) (Box 6)
    - Confessional [Play], ( Playscript (carbon copy) (Box 6)
    - Confetti [Short Story] See: Design in Confetti [Short Story] (Box 6)
    - Could Be [Short Story] See: A Hollywood Fable [Short Story] (Box 6)
    - Counterfeit Heaven [film], ( Typescript film treatment (carbon copy) (Box 6)
      [unproduced.]
    - The Day of Atonement [Short Story], Everybody's Magazine, 1922, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 7)
      [Earliest Version of The Jazz Singer]
    - Design in Confetti [Short Story], 1948, ( Typescript, ) (Box 7)
    - Design in Confetti [Short Story], ( Typescript (3 carbon copies) (Box 7)
    - Design in Confetti [Short Story], Esquire, 1948, ( Tearsheets (2 copies) (Box 7)
    - Debora and John [Play] See: Here We Are, Alone Together [Play] (Box 7)
    - Domestic Episode [Short Story], Good Housekeeping, 1944, ( Tearshteets, ) (Box 7)
    - The Dover Road [film], 1931, ( Scenario (bound mimeograph copy) (Box 7)
    - Eleven Short Stories [Anthology], ( Typescript (contents page), ) (Box 7)
    - Epaulettes for Everybody [Play], 194[?], ( Radio script, ) (Box 7)
    - Everybody Is Wonderful [Play] See: [Jason] My Severest Critic [Play] (Box 7)
    - Eyes for No Other Woman [Short Story], Snappy Stories, 1925, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 7)
    - Fable [Play], 1947, ( Playscript (original version), ) (Box 7)
    - Fable [Play], ( Playscript (2nd version) (Box 7)
    - Fable [Play], ( Playscript ("Thelma version") (Box 7)
    - Fable [Play], 1947, ( Notes & drafts, ) (Box 7)
    - The Family Circle [Play] See: [Jason] The Family Circle [Play] (Box 7)
    - Father Goes to College [film], ( Typescript (film treatment, carbon) (Box 7)
    - The First Affair [Short Story] See: After the Ball [Short Story] (Box 7)
    - Going Up [Short Story], ( Typescript (carbon), ) (Box 8)
      [Unpublished]
    - The Good Fairy [film], 1941, ( Scenario (carbon), ) (Box 8)
    - Goodbye Lady [Play] See: [Skylark] Goodbye Lady [Play] (Box 8)
    - Goodbye Mama, Goodbye Papa [Play] See: Here We Are, Alone Together [Play] (Box 8)
    - The Greatest Idea In The World [Short Story], ( Typescript (2 carbon copies) (Box 8)
    - The Greatest Idea In The World [Short Story], Good Housekeeping, 1946, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 8)
    - The Green Fig [Play] See: Here We Are, Alone Together [Play] (Box 8)
    - The Guitar [Short Story], 1976, ( Typescripts & notes, ) (Box 8)
    - Hamburgers in Hollywood [film] See: Two Little People [film] (Box 9)
    - The Happiness of Rebecca [Short Story] See: 0VERSIZE (Box 9)
    - He and She [Play] See: Israeli Play [Play] (Box 9)
    - He Found Himself [film], 1941, ( Typescript screen story (carbon copy) (Box 9)
    - He Wanted to Marry a Rich Girl [Short Story] See: Marry for Money [film] (Box 9)
    - Heaven Can Wait [film], 1943, ( Screenplay (Xerox copy) (Box 9)
    - Heaven Can Wait [film], 1981, ( Screenplay, edited for publication (2 xerox copies) (Box 9)
    - Heaven Can Wait [film], 1981, ( Screenplay, edited for publication: "Wisc. transcript" (Xerox copy) (Box 9)
    - Heaven Can Wait [film], Seminar at the Museum of Modern Art, 1977, ( Transcripts, etc., ) (Box 9)
    - Heaven Can Wait [film], Seminar at the Smithsonian, 1975[?], ( Transcript (Xerox copy) (Box 9)
    - Heaven Can Wait [film], 1972-1980, ( Reviews & printed misc., ) (Box 9)
    - The Heel [Play] See: [Boolie] The Heel [Play] (Box 9)
    - The Helen Morgan Story [film], 1956, ( Typescript film treatment, ) (Box 9)
    - Hello and Goodbye [Play], ( Synopsis and some dialogue, ) (Box 9)
    - Here We Are, Alone Together [Play], 1955-1975, ( Playscripts, ) (Box 10)
    - Here We Are, Alone Together [Play], 1950-1982, ( Notes, novella, & related materials, ) (Box 11)
    - The High Sign [Play] See: [Boolie] The High Sign [Play] (Box 12)
    - Hilda Benson [Hilda Crane. Novel], 1943-1947, ( Typescripts & notes, ) (Box 12)
      [See also: Beautiful Morning [Short Story] -- Jingle Bells [Short Story] -- Lost on 44th Street [Short Story] -- My Shining Palace [Short Story] -- Not the Cushion and the Slipper [Short Story] -- The Parson's Waiting [Short Story] -- Song At Twilight [Short Story]]
    - Hilda Crane [Play], 1950, ( Playbills, ) (Box 12)
    - Hilda Crane [Play], 1950, ( Reviews (clippings) (Box 12)
    - Hollywood Encounter [Short Story] See: A Hollywood Fable [Short Story] (Box 12)
    - A Hollywood Fable [Short Story], 1975-1979, ( Typescripts (drafts & notes) (Box 12)
    - A Hollywood Fable [Short Story], Atlantic Monthly, 1980, ( Proofs & tearsheets, ) (Box 12)
    - Home Sweet Home [Play] See: Here We Are, Alone Together [Play] (Box 12)
    - Honey [Play], 1938, ( Unfinished drafts, etc., ) (Box 12)
    - I Have the Greatest Respect [Play] See: One In a Billion [Play] (Box 13)
    - I Said To Myself [Series of Columns], Saucy Stories, 1923, ( Proofs & tearsheets, ) (Box 13)
    - I'm a Stranger Here [Dramatic Sketch], ca. 1938, ( Playscript (carbon copy) (Box 13)
    - I'm Mavis, the Irish Girl. [Short Story], 1947-1976, ( Typescripts, ) (Box 13)
    - I'm Mavis, the Irish Girl. [Short Story], 1947-1976, ( Notes, ) (Box 13)
    - In My Opinion [Play] See: [Jason] In My Opinion [Play] (Box 13)
    - Israeli-American Play [film], ca. 1970, ( Playscripts (carbon copies) (Box 13)
    - Israeli-American Play [film], 1970, ( Screenplay (carbon copy) (Box 13)
    - Israeli Play [Play], 1972-1980, ( Playscripy, ) (Box 13)
    - Israeli Play [Play], 1973-1980, ( Notes, ) (Box 13)
    - It Was a Pleasure [Short Story] See: Mother's Day [Short Story] See: Rough Treatment [Short Story] (Box 13)
    - Jason [Play], 1941, ( Playscript, ) (Box 14)
    - Jason [Play], ( Television script (carbon copy) (Box 14)
    - Jason [Play], ( Television script (mimeograph copy) (Box 14)
    - Jason [Play], ( Programs & misc., ) (Box 14)
    - Jason [Play], 1942-1947, ( Reviews (clippings) (Box 14)
    - Jason [Play] The Family Circle [Play], 1940, ( Playscript, ) (Box 14)
    - Jason [Play] In My Opinion [Play], 1940, ( Playscripts (3 drafts) (Box 14)
    - Jason [Play] My Severest Critic [Play], 1940-1941, ( Playscripts (drafts) (Box 14)
    - The Jazz Singer [Play], ( Playscript, ) (Box 15)
      [Samson Raphaelson did not write the film adaptation]
    - The Jazz Singer [Play], 1925, ( Playscript, ) (Box 15)
    - The Jazz Singer [Play], 1925, ( Playscript, ) (Box 15)
      [Intermediate version (mimeograph copy)]
    - The Jazz Singer [Play], ( Reviews, etc., ) (Box 15)
      [See also: OVERSIZE]
    - The Jazz Singer [Play], 1925-1981, ( Misc., ) (Box 15)
    - The Jazz Singer [Play] See also: The Day of Atonement [Short Story] (Box 15)
    - The Jazz Singer [Black Musical], 1975, ( Playscripts, ) (Box 15)
    - The Jazz Singer [Black Musical, 1975, ( Notes, ) (Box 15)
    - Jingle Bells [Short Story - Hilda Benson], Good Housekeeping, 1947, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 15)
    - Kati [Short Story], 1949, ( Typescripts, ) (Box 15)
    - Kati [Short Story], Cosmopolitan, 1949, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 15)
    - King With Umbrella [Play][ Suggested by a play by Ralph Benatzky], 1938, ( Playscript (carbon copy) (Box 15)
    - King With Umbrella [Play]. Playscript by Benatzky ("The King With the Umbrella"), ( Carbon copy, ) (Box 15)
    - Kingdom Come [Play] See: Fable [Play] (Box 15)
    - Last Day in Paris [Short Story], NBC, 1957, ( Radio script, ) (Box 16)
      [Adapted by Edward Nolan for NBC 1957]
    - Last Day in Paris [Short Story], 1957, ( Typescript, ) (Box 16)
    - Last Day in Paris [Short Story], The Saturday Evening Post, 1957, (Tearsheets ) (Box 16)
    - Lavender and Old Louse ["A Skit"], ( Typescript (carbon copy) (Box 16)
    - Leave 'em Smiling [film], ( Typescript (film treatment) (Box 16)
    - Letter to the Editor [Short Story], Good Housekeeping, 1950, ( Tearsheets (3 copies) (Box 16)
    - A Life of Her Own [film], 1949, ( Scenario (mimeographed) (Box 16)
      [Not used for produced film]
    - Lila [Play & Novella] See: Here We Are, Alone Together [Play] (Box 16)
    - Long Live the King [Play], 1937, ( Playscript (draft) (Box 16)
    - Long Live the King [Play], 1937, ( Playscript (carbon copy) (Box 16)
    - Lost On 44th Street (Short Story - Hilda Benson), 1946, ( Typescripts (carbon copies) (Box 16)
    - Lost On 44th Street (Short Story - Hilda Benson), Good Housekeeping, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 16)
    - The Madness of Men (Series), Snappy Stories, 1925, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 16)
    - The Magnificent Heel [Play] See: [Boolie] The Magnificent Heel [Play] (Box 16)
    - Main Street To Broadway [film], ( Screenplay (draft, carbon copy) (Box 16)
    - Main Street To Broadway [film], 1952, ( Screenplay (draft, mimeograph copy) (Box 16)
    - Main Street To Broadway [film], 1952, ( Screenplay (mimeograph copy) (Box 16)
    - Man and Wife [Play] See: [Skylark] Man and Wife [Play] (Box 17)
    - The Man I Killed [also, Broken Lullabye] [film], 1931, ( Scenario (Xerox copy) (Box 17)
    - A Man Is Entitled Once In a While To a Whim [Short Story] See: The Guitar [Short Story] (Box 17)
    - Marry For Money [film], ( Typescript film treatment, ) (Box 17)
    - The Merry Widow [film], 1934, ( Scenario (Xerox copy) (Box 17)
    - The Middle-aged Freshman [Short Story], ( Typescript (carbon copy) (Box 17)
    - The Middle-aged Freshman [Short Story], ( Radio script (mimeograph copy) (Box 17)
    - Mike Miller [Play] [later called The Store], 1926, ( Typescript, ) (Box 17)
    - Mike Miller [Play] [later called The Store], ( Typescript (variant, carbon copy) (Box 17)
    - The Miracle [film], ( Screenplay (carbon copy of draft) (Box 17)
    - Mr. Bystander and Miss Passerby [Short Story], ( Typescript, ) (Box 17)
    - Moonlight and Roses [film] [American-Isreali Film Project], 1970, ( Typescripts (drafts) (Box 17)
      [See also: Israeli-American Play [film]]
    - Moonlight Sonata [Short Story], ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 17)
    - Mother's Day [Short Story], ( Typescript drafts & notes, ) (Box 17)
      [See also: Rough Treatment [Short Story]]
    - The Music Shop [film], 1930, ( Screenplay (carbon copy) (Box 18)
    - My Boy [film], ( Outline & dialogue, carbon copy 1929, ) (Box 18)
    - My Friend Leo (Play by Joseph Patrick McEvoy), ( Notes & revisions by Raphaelson, ) (Box 18)
    - My Severest Critic [Play] See: [ My Severest Critic - Play] (Box 18)
    - My Shining Palace [Short Story - Hilda Benson], Good Housekeeping, 1947, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 18)
    - The New Green Fig [Play] See: Here We Are, Alone Together [Play] (Box 18)
    - Not the Cushion and the Slipper [Short Story - Hilda Benson], Good Housekeeping, 1947, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 18)
    - Old Couple in New York [Play] See: Israeli Play [Play] (Box 18)
    - The Old Gentleman [Short Story], 1974, ( Typescript (Xerox copy) (Box 18)
    - The Old Gentleman [Short Story], ( Notes, ) (Box 18)
    - Old Love [Film, not produced] See: Counterfeit Heaven [film] (Box 18)
    - One Hour With You [film], 1931, ( Scenario (Xerox copy) (Box 18)
    - One In a Billion [Play], 1974 & 1975, ( Playscript (drafts & notes) (Box 18)
    - The One Life of Erwin Barrows [Short Story] See: The Middle-aged Freshman [Short Story] (Box 18)
    - Opus Minus One (Poem), ( Typescript, ) (Box 18)
    - Palm Springs Musical [Play], 1953, ( Note, ) (Box 18)
    - The Parson's Waiting [Short Story - Hilda Benson], Good Housekeeping, 1947, ( Tearsheets, ) (Box 18)
    - The Peanut Bag [Play] See: Here We Are, Alone Together[Play] (Box 18)
    - The Perfect Marriage [Play], 1946, ( Playscript (carbon copy) (Box 18)
      ["Die Vollkommene Ehe" (German translation of SR's play)]
    - The Perfect Marriage [Play], 1960, ( Notes for a musical, ) (Box 18)
    - The Perfect Marriage [Play], 1944, ( Program, ) (Box 18)
    - Perhaps a Love Story [Short Story] See: A Hollywood Fable [Short Story] (Box 18)
    - Portrait of Jenny [Play - musical], 1960, ( Typescript (play treatment) (Box 18)
    - Portrait of Jenny [Play - musical], 1960, ( Notes, ) (Box 18)
    - A Prince in Disguise [Film, not produced], 1971, ( Screenplay, ) (Box 18)
    - A Prince in Disguise [Film, not produced], 1970-1971, ( Screenplays (drafts) (Box 18)
    - The Queen of Sheba (Play-musical) See: Sheba Musical [Play] (Box 18)
    - The Richest Woman In the Town [Short Story], ( Typescript, ) (Box 19)
    - The Richest Woman In the Town [Short Story], ( Typescript (carbon copy) (Box 19)
    - Roses Are Red [Play] See: [Jason] My Severest Critic [Play] (Box 19)
    - Rough Treatment [Short Story], 1957, ( Typescripts (carbon copy drafts) (Box 19)
    - Rough Treatment [Short Story], 1958, ( Radioscript (mimeograph copy) (Box 19)
      [Adaptation by Harriet Weber. See also: Mother's Day [Short Story]]
    - Servants' Entrance [film], ( Scenario (mimeographed copy) bound volume, ) (Box 19)
    - Sheba Musical [Play], ( Playscripts, ) (Box 19)
    - Sheba Musical [Play], 1954-1970, ( Outlines & notes, ) (Box 19)
    - Shelley Play [Play] See: Anniversary (a Shelley play). [Play] (Box 19)
    - Shirley Play [Play] See: Fable [Play] (Box 19)
    - Shop Around the Corner [film], [1939], ( Screenplay [Xerox copy], ) (Box 20)
    - Shop Around the Corner [film], (Revised 1980), ( Screenplay [Xerox copy of 1939 screenplay], ) (Box 20)
    - Shop Around the Corner [film], (Revised for publication 1981), ( Typescript, ) (Box 20)
    - [Shop Around the Corner] Parfumerie; a Comedy in Three Acts. By Miklos Laszlo, 1936 & 1957, ( Typescript of "Base Play" (Xerox copy) (Box 20)
    - [Shop Around the Corner] Parfumerie; a Comedy in Three Acts. By Miklos Laszlo, 1980, ( Misc., ) (Box 20)
    - Skylark [Play], ( Playscript (carbon copy) (Box 20)
      [Agent's copy]
    - Skylark [Play], ( Television scripts, ) (Box 20)
    - Skylark [Play], 1939-1984, ( Programs & misc., ) (Box 20)